Guide to the Washington Women United Records 1975-1986
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Washington Women United Records
1975-1986
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 529
Washington Women United
6 containers. 2.75 linear feet of shelf space.
Business records, correspondence, pamphlets, writings, and other records of the organization.
The statewide organization Washington Women United (WWU) was established in 1979 by Washington State Women's Political Caucus members as an independent unit to replace the services of the defunct Washington State Women's Council. WWU's primary purpose is to promote equal rights through legislative action, education, and networking. Members include individuals and organizations who are advocates of women's rights and proponents of the Equal Rights Amendment. Membership dues and pledges are the basis of support for WWU. The primary activity of WWU is to lobby the Washington State Legislature on issues of especial concern to women such as child care programs, domestic violence, abortion, comparable worth, and education. An annual poll of members determines WWU's position and lobbying priorities and guides its legislative efforts. The group maintains a staff, office, and full-time lobbyist in Olympia, and coordinates a statewide referral and information service on legislative activity. In addition, WWU provides telephone lists, mailing lists, a hot-line telephone service, information on lobbying techniques, news releases on political positions and issues, annual meetings, and six yearly newsletters. The organization also sponsors an annual legislative reception for elected officials which allows women to become acquainted with their legislators.
Officers are elected by and from the Board of Directors, and include: President, First Vice-President, Second Vice-President for Eastern Washington, Third Vice-President for Western Washington.
The records consist of the business records of the organization and contemporary information about the state legislature.
The collection is organized as five series: Business Records, Correspondence, Miscellanea, Women's Legislative Reception Reports, and Writings. All papers are arranged chronologically within each file.
Business Records contain Board of Directors election results, committee reports, financial information, meeting agendas and reports, membership lists and deliquencies, minutes of meetings, and policies and bylaws. The Board of Directors meeting minutes are filed under the heading "Minutes."
Within the Correspondence files are letters and memoranda to the Board of Directors, general correspondence and memoranda, and thank-you letters to legislators. Letters from legislators to WWU are in the general correspondence files. A photograph of Linda Clifton, WWU President for 1981, is filed in the Board of Directors Letters folder.
The Miscellanea series contains files on statewide general elections, King County Women's Political Caucus Candidate Questionnaires, original forms and letters of the organization, information on other organizations, pamphlets on WWU complete with application forms, and other materials.
The Women's Legislative Reception Reports series contains information on the organizers of the Reception, attendance lists of legislators and the public, and invitations to the event.
The Writings series includes a booklet documenting the Fifth Annual Meeting, the book IMPACT: A Woman's Guide to Legislative Action, legislative reports and newsletters, and the WWU newsletters.
This collection is open for research use.
The records of the Washington Women United, of Olympia, Washington, were donated to the Washington State University Libraries by the organization in July 1986 (MS 86-25).
A second installation of records from this organization was received and processed in 1995, as Cage 625.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington Women United--Archives
Women's rights--Washington (State)--Societies, etc.--Records and correspondence
Washington (State); Women; Government and Politics
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1: Business Records
  - Board of Directors
    - Agendas and Related Materials, undated; 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Elections
      - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Committees
    - Board of Directors Committee Reports, undated; 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Committee Roster and Sign-ups, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Education and Communication Committee Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Finance Committee Recommendations, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Membership Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Finances, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Forms and Letterhead, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Legislative Task Force and Workshops, undated; 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meetings
    - Annual
      - undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Board of Directors
      - January 30 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - March 27 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - May 15 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - June 25 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - September 18 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - November 6 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Memberships
    - Corporate Members, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Former Organizational Members and Deliquencies, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Membership Fee Payment (oversize folder), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Organizational Members, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes
    - Board of Directors Meetings
      - 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Executive Committee Meetings, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - First Meetings, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Implementing Board of Directors Meeting, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Policies and Bylaws, undated; 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Telephone Number Lists, undated; 1979; 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Series 2: Correspondence
  - Board of Directors
    - Letters, undated; 1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Memoranda, undated; 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - General
    - undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - January-June 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - July-December 1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - January-June 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - July-December 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - January-June 1982 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - July-December 1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda, undated; 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Thank-you Letters to Legislators
    - 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Series 3: Miscelllanea
  - Displaced Homemaker Organization, 1980; 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General Elections of 1982, undated; 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - House Standing Committee Assignments and Senate Standing Committee and Committee Assignments, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Issue Poll, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - King County Women's Political Caucus
    - State Legislative Candidate Interview Questions, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Candidate Questionnaires, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Legislative Platforms of other organizations, undated; 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Miscellanea, undated; 1975; 1979-1980; 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Original Forms and Form Letters
    - undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Pending Requests for Membership Information and Options for Typewriter Rental/Lease/Purchase, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Tax Surveys, undated; 1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Series 4: Women's Legislative Reception Reports
  - 1975-1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - 1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1981 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series 5: Writings
  - Fifth Annual Meeting of Washington Women United Meeting Booklet and Flyer, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - IMPACT: A Woman's Guide to Legislative Action, 1984 (?) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets with Membership Applications, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Washington Women United Legislative Reports and Legislative Newsletters, 1979-1982; 1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Washington Women United newsletters, 1979-1982; 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Information for publication in newsletters, undated; 1979; 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)